

SANJANA DANAIT

ARCHITECT | UX DESIGNER

I am an architectural designer, in the process of transitioning to a career in UX research and design. I am focused on creating meaningful experiences through design, enhancing human-product interaction through creative problem solving and am passionate about learning new things everyday.

CONTACT



+91-8308843680



sanjana2397@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/sanjana-danait-43622a1a9/



SKILLS

DESIGN:

Personas
Wireframing
Low to High Fidelity Prototyping
User reasearch
Usability Testing
Illustration and Visual Design

TOOLS:

Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Adobe XD MS Office

PROGRAMMING:

HTML CSS Javascript

LANGUAGES:

English Marathi Hindi German (Beginner)

COURSES/ CERTIFICATIONS

- Web Development Bootcamp by Angela Yu- Udemy | 2020
- User Experience Design
 Fundamentals by Joe Natoli-Udemy | 2020
- UX Design Essentials Adobe XD by Daniel Scott- Udemy | 2020
- Design for Humanity: A new perspective on User Experience by Eric Mayer- Udemy | 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancing | Dec 2020-Jan 2021

UX Research and E-commerce Website Design for Aakriti- Redefining Scrap Status: Design Complete, Development: Ongoing

- Conducted user research, interviews and user testing.
- Designed the site map, wireframes, prototypes, and the final UI for the website.
- Co-ordination with developer.

Intern Architect | Nov 2018-May 2019

SJK Architects | Mumbai

Under the guidance of Ar. Shimul Javeri Kadri, Ar. Vaishali Shankar & Ar. Arunima Dubey, worked on the design resolution, integration and execution stages of an Administrative & Research facility and a Hospitality project.

- Worked on design development, site execution drawings, and architectural detailing.
- Handled co-ordination and meetings with various consultants and vendors.
- Attended client presentations and meetings.
- Learned to inculcate the use of 'SCRUM'- a project management framework to address complex adaptive problems and to help teams structure and manage their work.

Assistant Set Designer | April 2017-May 2017

FTII- Art Direction Dept. | Pune

Worked with FTII students- Art Director Neeraj Singh and team to make a miniature set for the diploma short film "Ekaant" directed by Sarthak Bhasin.

- Played an important part in the research, exploration, experimentation and development of materials, textures & scale to make the set as realistic as possible.
- The film travelled to various festivals, and won many awards, the most notable of which are:
- The 66th National Film Award for Art Direction- "For it's surrealistic design and imagery of a bleak impending catastrophe". Honored by the Vice President of India at Vigyan Bhavan Delhi.
- Best Short Fiction Award at the Tbilisi International Student Film Festival.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Architecture | B.Arch | 2020

7.05/10 (CGPA)

Rachana Sansad's Academy of Architecture | Mumbai

- Teaching Assistant | 2019-20
- Co-head: NASA Reuben's Trophy Special Mention & Team member: LeCorbusier Trophy at ANC, Jaipur | 2017-18
- Team member for NASA Reuben's Trophy: Special Mention at ANC, Surat | 2016-17

Higher Secondary Certificate | 12th Std. | 2015

82.77%

D.G. Ruparel College of Science | Mumbai

Secondary School Certificate | 10th Std. | 2013

92.55%

Abhinava Vidyalaya English Medium School | Pune